Luis Esteban Serrano Bermúdez

Computer Engineer - Hardware Engineer

PERSONAL DATA

Born February 19, 1992 Phone (+52) 55-3015-9182 Number

E extstyle -Mail LESerranoB@outlook.com

Linkedin www.linkedin.com/in/leserranobz/

Github www.github.com/LESerrB/

INTRODUCTION

I introduce myself, I am a student who is in the process of degree having concluded with the corresponding credits of the career I seek to start generating work experience in the area I studied and apply what I have learned over the time I spend as a fellow and as an engineering student.

In addition to my training in the faculty I have taken courses to expand my knowledge in different programming languages as well as different ways of visualizing a problem.

I look forward to having the opportunity to discuss this position and what I can do. If you need any additional information, feel free to contact me.

EDUCATION

Computer Engineer

2014-2020 (Graduate without

National Autonomus University of Mexico - Faculty of Engineering

• Specialty: Hardware Engineering

Courses and Seminars

• Programming with C# intermediate level

July 22 - 26, 2019

Computing Training program of the Civil Engineering and Geomatics Division, Facultad de Ingeniería UNAM.

10 hour course.

ID: F092019C069C0726

• Latex general level

July 29 - august 2, 2019

Computing Training program of the Civil Engineering and Geomatics Division, Facultad de Ingeniería UNAM.

10 hour course.

ID: F092019C084C0706

• Matlab & Simulink Fundamentals

January 13 - 17, 2020

UNAM Student Branch of the Institute of Electronics of Electrical Engineers.

20 hour course.

ID: FII-EL-2020-C002-R025

$\bullet\,$ Matlab & Simulink with applications in Digital Signal Processing and Control.

January 20 - 24, 2020

UNAM Student Branch of the Institute of Electronics of Electrical Engineers.

20 hour course.

ID: FII-EL-2020-C005-R017

• Introduction to Data Science with R

March 7 - may 2, 2020

Faculty of Engineering, UNAM

48 hour course.

• Complete Excel Online Course.

November 1 - 5, 2020

Udemy

8 hour course.

ID: UC-a46009ef-e220-471b-a1a6-da5a92526863.

www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-a46009ef-e220-471b-a1a6-da5a92526863

• The Complete Front-End Web Development Course! September 21 - november 8, 2020

Impartido por: Udemy

17 hour course.

ID: UC-4c3b7d5d-03e3-4ecb-8ad1-229ea50b5a4c.

www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-4c3b7d5d-03e3-4ecb-8ad1-229ea50b5a4c/

• Introduction to programming with Python

November 5 - 9, 2020

Coursera

17 hour course.

ID: HKEEVSU5KJNE.

 $\verb|www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/HKEEVSU5KJNE| \\$

• Data structures in Python

November 9 - 18, 2020

Course ra

15 hour course.

ID: 7HXJ98WUHZJH.

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/7HXJ98WUHZJH

• Object Oriented Programming with Python

November 18 - 30, 2020

Course ra

9 hour course.

ID: 8P6289HGBVLU.

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/8P6289HGBVLU

• Managing databases with Python

November 30 - december 5, 2020

Coursera

16 hour course.

ID: 56BD6M4EBRUR.

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/56BD6M4EBRUR

• Git for Developers Using Github

December 1st, 2020

Coursera

ID: QVPSER5GA99V.

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/QVPSER5GA99V

• Technician in installation and repair of computer equipment

December 3rd, 2020

Train for employment. Carlos Slim Foundation.

ID: w4lmu59hr.

www.capacitateparaelempleo.org/verifica/w4lmu59hr/

• Technician in laptop repair

December 4, 2020

Train for employment. Carlos Slim Foundation.

ID: 6idky4b1f.

www.capacitateparaelempleo.org/verifica/6idky4b1f/

• Introduction to Economics

November 30, 2020

Train for employment. Carlos Slim Foundation.

ID: vf7e4ztnw.

www.capacitateparaelempleo.org/verifica/vf7e4ztnw/

• Economic Culture (Introduction)

December 2, 2020

 $Train\ for\ employment.\ Carlos\ Slim\ Foundation.$

ID: 83yljvwa1.

www.capacitateparaelempleo.org/verifica/83yljvwa1/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sewing workshop assistant

2010 - 2016

Family business

• Part-time assistant in the repair of half-workshop sewing machines, order deliveries and material and sewing of straight machine and zigzag knee pads.

Firmware developer

2018 - 2020

Engineering Institute UNAM

- Wrote the code for update time of a microcontroller through sync with an NTP server.
- Developed an enhancement of a file storage system for a microcontroller on a micro SD card through SPI communication, with access to the files through a web page.
- Support with seismic signals sampling on a shaking table with microcontrollers and accelerometers through a personal computer on a network.

System Assistant

2020 - Now

Linoleums 21

- Administrator of Zafiro ERP software. Purchase, Sales and personal management.
- Sopport with inventories.
- Data backup management.

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Languages Spanish (native)

English (intermediate, no certification)

Programming Latex, C, C++, C#, VHDL, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Java,

Languages MATLAB, R, Python, Git.

Software Microsoft Office, Proteus, LabView

Soft skills Teamwork

Flexibility Adaptability Problem solving Responsibility Work Ethic

Skills Carpenter, Electrician, Plumber and

Mechanics Saavy.